Finding Aid for L. Brooks Patterson papers, 1975-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Speeches
  - 2006-2007
    - MOIA Forensics Conference 2006, June 14, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Housing Needs Assessment Form August 29, 2006 (Box 3)
    - 10th Anniversary Celebration of International Academy September 21, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Leslie Murphy and Merton Segal Video Scripts November 1, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Great Lakes National Cemetery November 11, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Delmia/Oakland Schools Partnership November 17, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Oakland County Competitive Business Robotics Awards November 30, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Kettering University Commencement Address December 9, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Oakland County Economic Outlook Luncheon April 26, 2007 (Box 3)
    - Troy Property Showcase June 7, 2007 (Box 3)
- Roasts 1976-2004
  The Roasts series consists of the comments made by Patterson at a variety of roasts and other celebratory events in the period of 1976 to 2004. These appearances further document Patterson's active participation in Oakland County and the wide range of his friends and colleagues.
  - 1976-1989
    - Celebrity Roast 1976 (Box 3)
    - James Bonnel Retirement Party May 4, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Roast of Dick Campbell August 23, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Nora Grant Retirement Party May 24, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Lew Wint Roast October 25, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Jack Kemp Kick-Off to Victory Dinner December 5, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Roast of Jim Hand February 29, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Toast for Bob And Delores Conaway Wedding May 19, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Isaiah Thomas Roast November 8, 1984 (Box 3)
    - West Bloomfield Chamber Breakfast May 24, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Bill Lucas Night September 1985 (Box 3)
    - Roast of Jaro Kolisnyk October 11, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Lance Parrish Roast November 7, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Farewell Luncheon for Chief James Hildebrand January 31, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Roast of J.P. McCarthy May 28, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Tim Skubick Roast February 24, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Bill Lambier Roast December 6, 1987 (Box 3)
    - Dick Vitale Roast March 1998 (Box 3)
    - George Kuhn Testimonial Dinner September 12, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Paul Gadola Roast February 3, 1989 (Box 3)
  - 1990-1993
    - Chuck Daly Roast March 6, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Jim Stewart Retirement Party March 29, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Judge Carl F. Ingraham Retirement Dinner March 29, 1990 (Box 3)
    - St. Clair County Event April 28, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Denny McCain Roast June 18, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Bob Teremi Roast August 25, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Earl Kreps Farewell Party September 13, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Al Dittrich Salute December 5, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Nifty Norman's Golf Outing June 17, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Mort Crim Roast March 12, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Jerry Thick Roast April 13, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Duke Reynolds Retirement June 21, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Rich Fisher Roast April 9, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Hoot McInerny Roast April 14, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Spence Abraham 49th Birthday June 19, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Lynn Allen's Birthday June 20, 1992 (Box 3)
    - OIC Banquet September 11, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Del Lohff Retirement September 17, 1992 (Box 3)
    - Jo Muer Charity Roast May 25, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Ken Calvert Roast June 7, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Salute to Justice June 16, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Eli and Denny Roast August 9, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Councilman Jack Kelly October 18, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Washington D.C. Octoberfest October 27, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Lt. Col. Clarence Harvey November 18, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Bernie Smilovich Roast November 18, 1993 (Box 3)
  - 1994-2000
    - Rudy Lozano Roast March 5, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Sheriff John Nichols Roast March 24, 1994 (Box 3)
    - J.P. McCarthy Roast June 13, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Norm Shirkle July 19, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Jim Alexander Golf Outing September 25, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Jack Hays Retirement Dinner October 12, 1994 (Box 3)
    - Young Presidents Organization November 13, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Honorable Robert Templin Tribute Dinner January 17, 1997 (Box 3)
    - Roy Roberts Roast March 8, 1997 (Box 3)
    - Mickey Shapiro Roast October 14, 1998 (Box 3)
    - Answer to LBP Birthday Roast at Indianwood January 9, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Carl Marlinga Roast May 18, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Pat Elwell Roast November 4, 1999 (Box 3)
    - David Gorcyca/Joe Knollenberg Roast November 30, 1999 (Box 3)
    - Chief John Dean Promotion Party January 11, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Tony Soave Birthday January 15, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Gorcyca Roast American Polish Cultural Center May 3, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Senator Mike Rogers Roast May 30, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Marianne Nestor Retirement Celebration Pine Lake Country Club June 27, 2000 (Box 3)
    - John Welker Roast July 29, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Gus Cifelli Retirement Dinner November 14, 2000 (Box 3)
  - 2001-2004
    - John Mahoney Retirement Dinner January 5, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Roast of Freman Hendrix March 10, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Celebration Night 2001, May 8, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Barry Howard Roast May 11, 2001 (Box 3)
    - Russ Carniak Roast June 13, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Judge Kenneth Hempstead Retirement December 4, 2002 (Box 3)
    - Fred Harris Retirement February 6, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Richard Thompson Roast May 15, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Frank McCartney August 15, 2003 (Box 4)
    - Mike Duggen Dinner February 17, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Undated
    - Russ Rey Dinner (Box 4)
    - Gene Schnelz (Box 4)
    - CCA Outing (Box 4)
    - Richard Thompson and Marlyn Harty Wedding (Box 4)
    - Introduction of Ronna Romney (Box 4)
- Press
  The Press series includes photocopies of articles by and about Patterson; newspaper opinion pieces or letters to the editor of the Oakland Press and the two Detroit newspapers; and press releases from the Oakland County Executive's office.
  - Newspaper Clippings 1976-1987
    - Special Projects 1974 (Box 4)
    - Organized Crime 1975-1981 (Box 4)
    - The Criminal Justice System (Box 4)
    - Patterson Campaign 1978 (Box 4)
    - Prison Issue (Box 4)
    - Pontiac Police Department 1978-1981 (Box 4)
    - Welfare Reform 1978-1981 (Box 4)
    - Pornography 1978-1981 (Box 4)
    - Plea Bargaining 1978-1981 (Box 4)
    - Parole Reform 1978 (Box 4)
    - Capital Punishment 1978 (Box 4)
    - Patterson for Senate 1978 (Box 4)
    - Patterson Political 1981 (Box 4)
    - Perpetrators 1984-1985 (Box 4)
    - Capital Punishment 1986 (Box 4)
    - Death Penalty 1987 (Box 4)
    - Legislation 1986 (Box 4)
    - ACLU Lawsuit 1986 (Box 4)
    - Opposition 1986 (Box 4)
    - Death Penalty 1980-1984 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous 1978-1984, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Public Opinion 1986 (Box 4)
    - Polls 1984-1988 (Box 4)
    - Petition Drives 1984-1987 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous criminal cases 1979-1981 (Box 4)
    - Opposition 1982 (Box 4)
    - Public opinion 1980-1982 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Articles 1982 (Box 4)
  - Editorials / Letters to the Editor 1976-2007
    - 1976-1984 (Box 4)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 4)
    - 1993 (Box 4)
    - 1994-1998, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - 2000-2002 (Box 4)
    - 2005 (Box 4)
    - 2006 (Box 4)
    - 2007 (Box 4)
  - Press Releases 1999-2007
    - Airport 1999-2007 (Box 4)
    - Administration 2003-2007 (Box 4)
    - Animal Control 1999-2007 (Box 4)
    - Automation Alley 1999-2007 (Box 4)
    - Arts Culture Film 2002-2007 (Box 4)
    - Business Roundtable 1999-2001 (Box 4)
    - Casual Day 2001-2007 (Box 4)
    - Children's Village 1999-2000 (Box 4)
    - Cobo Hall 2004-2005 (Box 4)
    - Community Connections 1999-2000 (Box 4)
    - Community and Home Improvement 2004 (Box 4)
    - Corporation Counsel 2000-2002 (Box 4)
    - Courts undated (Box 4)
    - Covisint 2000-2002 (Box 4)
    - Economic Development Community Affairs 2000-2007 (Box 4)
    - Emergency Response Preparedness 2000-2007 (Box 4)
    - Employee Suggestion Program 1999-2005 (Box 4)
    - Employment and Training 2000-2001 (Box 4)
    - Equalization 2002-2003 (Box 4)
    - Executive Office 1999-2002 (Box 4)
    - Facilities Management 2000 (Box 4)
    - Golf Outing 2000 (Box 4)
    - Health 2000-2007 (Box 4)
    - Huber, Steve 2004 (Box 4)
    - Human Resource 2002-2007 (Box 4)
    - Information Technology 1999-2006 (Box 4)
    - Management and Budget 2000-2006 (Box 4)
    - Medical Care Facility 2001-2005 (Box 4)
    - Medical Examiner 2002-2003 (Box 4)
    - Michigan State University Extension 2005-2006 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous 1999-2002, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - NACO 2007 (Box 5)
    - Parenting Awareness 2005 (Box 5)
    - Prescription Relief Program 2004-2005 (Box 5)
    - Public Services 2002 (Box 5)
    - Quake on the Lake 2006 (Box 5)
    - Research Library 2004-2005 (Box 5)
    - Risk Management 2002 (Box 5)
    - Senior Citizen Advantage 2004-2007 (Box 5)
    - Sheriff 2001-2006 (Box 5)
    - Single Business Tax 2006 (Box 5)
    - Statements 2005-2006 (Box 5)
    - Support Services 2000-2006 (Box 5)
    - Treasurer's Office 2003-2005 (Box 5)
    - Veteran's Office 2003 (Box 5)
    - Waste Management 2002-2004 (Box 5)
    - Water 2003 (Box 5)
    - Website 2005 (Box 5)
    - Wellness Institute 2007 (Box 5)
    - Wireless Oakland 2005-2007 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous
  The Miscellaneous series includes proclamations, subject files, notes, political campaign information, and a few pieces of correspondence.
  - Arts Beats and Eats 1998-2003, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Bond Rating 2003-2005, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Child Abuse: The Dentist's Responsibility to Recognize and Report (Box 5)
  - Clinton County News 1978 (Box 5)
  - John Connally 1978 (Box 5)
  - Corp Magazine, Man of the Year, January-February 2000 (Box 5)
  - County Executive Platform (Box 5)
  - The Day the Power Went Out (Box 5)
  - Debates (Box 5)
  - Election 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Freeports/Free Trade Zone (Box 5)
  - Griffen (Box 5)
  - Groups (Box 5)
  - Lawsuit (Box 5)
  - Michigan Humane Society (foreword to book) March 9, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Notes (Box 5)
  - Priorities (Box 5)
  - Proclamations 2001-2007, 7 folders (Box 5)
  - Proposal for Property Tax (Box 5)
  - Seniors (Box 5)
  - September 11, 2001 Banner (Box 5)
  - Society of Professional Journalists (Box 5)
  - Tax Limitation (Box 5)
  - Washington (Box 5)
  - Willis Harris Case 1980 (Box 5)
  - Witherspoon Case 1980 (Box 5)
  - 216 Blitz (Box 5)
- Other media
  The Other Media series consist of seven videotapes from 1992 to 2005. They primarily contain campaign statements, publicity for the Oakland County Prescription Plan, and other laws. This series also consists of one CD with the files from Patterson's web site as of June 13, 2007.
  - Videotapes
    (vhs unless otherwise described)
    - New Underage Drinking Law undated, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 5)
    - Patterson for Co. Executive October 15, 1992, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 5)
    - Guest Editorial Telecast April 4-5 1993, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 5)
    - Oakland County Veteran's Memorial Dedication May 28, 1994, 1 videotapes Betacam (TM) (Box 5)
    - Comcast Newsmakers December 16, 2003, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 5)
    - Oakland County Prescription Plan April 14, 2005, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 5)
    - Oakland Prescription Plan, Summer 2005, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 5)
  - Oakland County Executive website CD, captured June 13, 2007, 1 optical disks CD-R (Box 1)
    (original URL www.oakgov.com/exec/)